ANTON POVZNER

South Bend, IN · apovzner@nd.edu · (574) 400-5789 · www.linkedin.com/in/anton-povzner/

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

With over three years of professional research experience and a decade of academic training, I produce nuanced analyses and communicate effectively to diverse audiences. I am used to managing tight deadlines on both individual and collaborative projects, and I am dedicated to cultivating relationships with colleagues and external stakeholders. I am excited to move to the next step in my career where I can apply my research expertise toward concrete positive impact in the world.

PROFESSIONAL RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

Research Consultant

Jerusalem, Israel

Charles and Lynn Schusterman Family Philanthropies—Israel

May - July 2021

- Investigated the structural challenges facing Arab communities in Israel, contributing to multiple investments in education non-profits.
- Generated a comparative review of government policies on a set of relevant issues.
- Consulted and produced reports under tight deadlines in both English and Hebrew.

Research and Strategy Analyst

Jerusalem & Tel Aviv, Israel 2013 - 2016

Start-Up Nation Central

- Conducted policy research, interpreting diverse sources to recommend the best course of action for internal partner teams.
- Developed and evaluated ideas in a collaborative setting to channel Israeli technological innovation toward positive social impact.
- Built productive relationships with external partners and stakeholders through personal meetings, presentations, and conference attendance; accompanied a foreign delegation of 15 innovation & entrepreneurship experts to learn about needs, secure partnerships and generate new ideas and initiatives.
- Contributed to a strategic vision document, which was presented at an executive meeting and used to realign the organization's efforts
- Worked both independently and as part of a team, managing deadlines and priorities on multiple projects at any given time.

RESEARCH TRAINING

MicroMasters Program Participant, Statistics and Data Science MITx

Remote

2022 - current

- Expanding my quantitative analysis skills to complement my extensive qualitative research training.
- Taking 4 classes in statistics, social science data analysis, and machine learning over the course of one year, culminating in a capstone exam.

Postdoctoral Fellow Notre Dame, IN

Center for Digital Scholarship, Notre Dame

2021 - current

- Collaborated across departments and wrote educational materials to develop a library collection and ensure that it would reach target audiences.
- Took lead on a vendor relationship, beta-testing a text-mining research platform and liaising between the vendor and the campus research community.
- Developed messaging strategies to promote university-wide adoption of research software, interfacing over 50 faculty, staff, and department stakeholders.
- Created accessible presentation materials, translating technical concepts for different audiences in a workshop series on text mining and research software.
- Quantitative text mining research: collected and cleaned a dataset of 2 million words, then used a broad range of methods to investigate topics of interest using Python programming and specialized software (MALLET, Gephi, MorphAdorner).

PhD Candidate, English

University of Notre Dame

Notre Dame, IN 2016 – 2021

- Practiced a wide range of critical approaches to our culture, modes of knowledge, politics, economy, and their intersections with one another.
- Conducted diverse types of literary research and writing addressing several hundred years of English-language cultures, continually managing competing priorities.
- Managed communication between scholars, editors and the press and performed various editing tasks as an editorial assistant at the *Early American Literature* journal.
- Provided quantitative text mining analysis and data manipulation as part of a collaborative interdisciplinary research project covering 24,000 pages of a 30-year magazine run.
- Constructed and taught 3 courses on literary-historical topics and on persuasive writing at the 100- and 200-levels to classes of 15-20 students.

Research Assistant; Doctoral Visiting Fellow

Jerusalem, Israel

"Apartheid—The Global Itinerary" Research Project

2014 – 2017

- Performed archival research as part of a 24-member interdisciplinary team examining the intersection of global Cold War politics and culture; work done in English and Russian.
- Established technical infrastructure for the team's internal learning management and knowledge preservation through Evernote, Zotero, Google Drive, and regular back-ups.

PUBLICATIONS, WRITING, AND PRESENTATIONS

Internal research projects ranging from on-the-spot inquiries to 30+ page deep-dives on policy or technology.

2013 - 2021

Individual and collaborative academic publications in peer-reviewed journals (*Modernism/Modernity Print Plus*, 2019) and edited volumes (*The Cultural Cold War and the Global South*, 2021).

Broad public-facing library guides: Legacy Technology Collection; Reference Management Software.

2021

Workshop presentations: Constellate (academic literature text-mining platform),

2021

MALLET (topic modeling), Mendeley (citation management), FineReader (scanning & OCR).

Academic conference presentations (Society of Early Americanists Eleventh Biennial Conference, 2019, MLA Annual Convention, 2020).

ADDITIONAL TRAINING

Computer Skills: Python (300+ hours), Microsoft Office and Google Workspace.

Online Courses: United States Health Policy (Harvard via edX); Health, Housing, and Educational Services (Columbia University via Coursera).

Languages: fully fluent in Hebrew and Russian.

EDUCATION

University of Notre Dame

Notre Dame, IN

2021

PhD, English; Graduate Minor in Gender Studies

Jerusalem, Israel

Hebrew University of Jerusalem MA, English Literature

2016

cum laude

BA, English Literature and the "Amirim"

2013

Interdisciplinary Honors Program in the Humanities

summa cum laude